n2games.com 2000-11-10

# Lycos Privacy Policy

**Navigating Lycos**  

**Tools**  

**Build**   

**Find**  

**Buy**   

| |  |     

  **Lycos Network Privacy Policy**

Welcome to the Lycos Network, owned and produced by Lycos, Inc. and its subsidiary and affiliate corporations, successors, and assigns (collectively referred to as "Lycos"). The Lycos Network Products and Services (collectively, the "Products and Services") are offered by Lycos through web pages at or linked to the URLs [www.lycos.com](http://www.lycos.com/),  [www.gamesville.com](http://www.gamesville.com/),  [www.tripod.com](http://www.tripod.com/),  [www.angelfire.com](http://www.angelfire.com/),  [www.quote.com](http://www.quote.com/),  [comm.lycos.com](http://comm.lycos.com/),  [htmlGEAR.com](http://htmlgear.lycos.com/),  [www.wired.com](http://www.wired.com/),  [www.hotwired.com](http://www.hotwired.com/),  [www.webmonkey.com](http://www.webmonkey.com/),  [www.whowhere.com](http://www.whowhere.com/),  [www.hotbot.com](http://www.hotbot.com/),  [www.lycoszone.com](http://www.lycoszone.com/), and [www.sonique.com](http://www.sonique.com/). (collectively referred to as the "Lycos Network," which may expand or change from time to time) are made available subject to this Privacy Policy. This statement discloses the privacy practices of the Lycos Network. By using the Products and Services, you agree, without limitation or qualification, to be bound by this Privacy Policy or any other privacy or data collection policy applicable to any individual Lycos Network web site. 

[](http://www.truste.org/users/users_lookup.html)**TRUSTe Certification**  
Lycos is TRUSTe certified. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit initiative whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the principles of disclosure and informed consent. Lycos wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy and has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed and audited for compliance by TRUSTe. The Lycos Network Privacy Policy contains detailed information about the following: 

| 1.  | What information of yours does the Lycos Network collect?  
---|---  
2.  | What are "cookies" and how does Lycos use them?  
3.  | What organization is collecting the information?  
4.  | How does the Lycos Network use the information?  
5.  | With whom does the Lycos Network share the information that is collected?   
6.  | How can you access, edit or delete your information?  
7.  | What is the opt-out policy for the Lycos Network?  
8.  | What types of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?  
9.  | **The Lycos Network’s Notice regarding the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)**  
10.  | What additional measures does the Lycos Network take to protect children online?  
11.  | What can you do to better protect yourself on the Internet?  
  
Contact information for questions regarding this statement should be directed to:

Lycos Privacy Site Coordinator   
Lycos, Inc.   
400-2 Totten Pond Road   
Waltham, MA 02154   
(781) 370-2700  
(781) 370-2600 (Fax)   

You may also contact [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/) for clarification about this privacy policy and the TRUSTe Seal Program generally:

**TRUSTe Certification**  
1180 Coleman Avenue, Suite 202  
San Jose, CA 95110  
(408) 342-1940  
(408) 342-1950 (Fax)  

Please note that the Lycos Network contains links to other sites and occasionally allows other sites to be co-branded with the Lycos name, and while we endeavor to ensure that these other sites' Privacy Policies conform to our own, Lycos cannot represent or guarantee that they do so. So bear in mind that sites that are linked to from Lycos Network sites, or carry the Lycos brand for co-branding or marketing purposes, may have privacy policies which differ from that of the Lycos Network. 

This policy may be updated from time to time so please check back periodically. 

**1\. What information of yours does the Lycos Network collect?**  
The goal of the Lycos Network is to be your favorite destination on the Internet by providing you with the information, services and product offerings that are most relevant to you. To achieve this goal, the Lycos Network needs to collect information to understand what differentiates you from its millions of other unique users. We collect two types of information from you, "anonymous information" and "personally identifiable information." Anonymous information refers to information that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. Each time a visitor comes to a Lycos Network site, Lycos collects some information to improve the overall quality of the visitor's online experience. Lycos collects the visitor's IP address (e.g., whether the user is logged on from a .com, .gov or .edu domain), referral data (e.g., the address of the last URL a user visited prior to clicking through to a Lycos Network site), and browser and platform type (e.g., a Netscape browser on a Macintosh platform). Lycos also collects aggregate search terms from its HotBot and Lycos search services for internal reporting and targeted advertising. Lycos collects this user information for purposes of product monitoring, product improvement, and targeted advertising. 

In addition to this anonymous data, Lycos may also collect personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information refers to information that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name and postal address. Wherever and whenever Lycos collects personal information through registration we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. Lycos collects personal information in the following ways from different parts of its network of web sites:

  1. Most of the personal information is gathered when you register with one or several of the Lycos Network sites. If you choose to register --and we hope you do-- you may provide Lycos with your name, postal address, email address, birth date, gender, zip code, telephone number, occupation, marital status and other information. While not all of this information is required, the more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register you are given a Lycos Network ID and are able to take full advantage of the many offerings around the Lycos Network, including personalization services. For example, My Lycos uses your network ID to offer you customized news, sports scores, weather reports, TV schedules and stock quotes. Lycos finds that users who personalize their Lycos experience come back more often. 
  2. In addition to registration for various services on the Network, Lycos may ask you for personal information at other times, including when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by the Lycos Network and/or our many partners. We also ask for information when you make a purchase using Lycos Shop, when you make travel arrangements using Lycos Travel and when you apply for a Club Lycos credit card. The number and variety of useful services the Lycos Network provides continues to grow and so will your ability to make use of these services if you choose to register for them. You never have to register for any of these services on the Lycos Network. This is true on any site on the Internet. If you choose not to provide the requested information, the Lycos Network may not be able to offer you some of the personalized services that depend on this type of information to function.
  3. If you contact the Lycos Network, we may keep a record of that correspondence. We do not collect any e-mail addresses of those who communicate with the Lycos Network via e-mail. We use the information provided so that we may respond to the e-mail. 

**2\. What are "cookies" and how does Lycos use them?**  
In addition to the personally identifiable information that Lycos collects, we also collect information "anonymously" using "cookies." Presently, "cookies" play an important role in making the Internet work, but there is much confusion among Internet users about what cookies are and how they are used. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a web site to the hard drive of your computer so that the web site may identify you and track your activities on the web site. This unique number identifies your browser-- but not you -- to Lycos computers whenever you visit one of the sites in the Lycos Network. A cookie will not let a web site know any personally identifiable information about you, such as your real name and address. Lycos is not generally interested in any one individual and does not collect personally identifiable information about any one person using cookies. The coding in the cookies Lycos sets lets us know that you are using a particular computer but nothing more. Since cookies are only text files, they cannot run on your computer, search your computer for other information or transmit any information to anyone. 

To help serve you better Lycos generally uses cookies to:

  * Help us remember who you are through your browser settings so that Lycos can offer and provide personalized services, such as My Lycos and Lycos Rewards. Lycos uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about whom has done and seen what across our Network of sites. Cookies also allow us to save passwords and preferences for you so that you will not have to re-enter them the next time you visit. 
  * Help merchants in Lycos Shop track business at their stores and process orders in individual shopping carts.
  * Measure traffic patterns. Without cookies, it could be difficult for Lycos to know that certain services are more popular than others are. This information helps us to better understand when to open up new services. 
  * Estimate audience size. Cookies help us know whether or not users have seen particular displays, including advertising, so we do not bore you with the same material over and over again.
  * Displaying advertisements. Third party advertising networks for Lycos may issue cookies when serving advertisements.

The use of cookies is now an industry standard, and you will find them used on most major web sites. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser either to notify you when you have received a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies. You should understand that while Lycos does not require you to use cookies, certain sites will not function properly if you set your browser to not accept cookies. 

**Lycos’ relationship with DoubleClick**  
Click here for information on Lycos’ relationship with DoubleClick

**3\. What organization is collecting the information**?   
When you register information in any Internet domain of the Lycos Network, that information is generally collected and maintained solely by the Lycos Network unless specifically stated otherwise at the point of collection. For example, some Lycos Network services, like Lycos Auctions, are offered in conjunction with a partner company. If data is collected and/or maintained by any company other than the Lycos Network, we will tell you at the point of collection. If you do not want to share your information with that company, you can choose not to use that service. Please see the Section entitled "With whom does the Lycos Network share information that is collected?" for a more complete list of companies that Lycos works with to provide you Products and Services.

Lycos runs many promotions and sweepstakes across its Network. These promotions may be sponsored or co-sponsored by third-parties. Data collected during a promotion is typically shared with the sponsor or co-sponsor. Lycos will inform you at the point of collection whether or not we are sharing your personal data as a result of your participation in a promotion or sweepstakes. If you do not want to have the Lycos Network share your data, you can choose not to participate in the promotion or sweepstakes.

Be aware that Lycos Network sponsors and other advertisers have links on our sites that take you to other sites that may collect personally identifiable information about you. Lycos hopes that all third parties involved adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our users. However, this Lycos Network Privacy Policy does not cover third party data collection practices and the Lycos Network does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties.   

**4\. How does the Lycos Network use the information it collects?**   
Any personal information you provide to Lycos when registering for Products and Services at any of its Network sites is maintained and accessible only by the Lycos Network unless specifically stated otherwise. Lycos requests information from its users so that users can enjoy customized experiences across the Lycos Network, including personalization services, interactive communications, games, online shopping and many other types of content and services. Most of these Products and Services are free to you. In order to provide great content and services free of charge, Lycos displays advertisements. 

The following are examples of how The Lycos Network may use the information it collects:

  * The Lycos Network offers its users the ability to personalize content on the Network, such as news, stock portfolios, weather reports, sports scores, movie and television listings, horoscopes and more.
  * Lycos uses the aggregate data collected to inform our sponsors as to numbers of people who have certain demographic characteristics and the number of those people who have seen and "clicked" on their advertisement(s). We will also disclose to those third-party sponsors the overall demographics available regarding who saw and "clicked" on their advertisement. No personally identifiable information will be disclosed to these advertisers as part of this process; only information in an aggregate form.
  * Lycos also uses the aggregate data to perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our registered users and visitors, to measure user demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the Lycos Network and to analyze how and where best to use our resources. Without such data, we would not know what the most popular areas of the Lycos Network are, and we would not be able to change and update the content and services appropriately.
  * The Lycos Network may, from time to time, use your information to contact you about changes or enhancements to Products and Services on the Lycos Network
  * If you told the Lycos Network that you were interested in receiving offers or information from selected Lycos Network sponsors and advertisers, Lycos will send you email about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. For those who elect to receive such materials from Lycos or third parties, and who indicate that they do in their profile, Lycos will release personally identifiable information. Information released includes name, e-mail address and other information supplied in the Lycos Network registration process. 
  * The Lycos Network sometimes uses an individual registered user’s data to "pre-populate" forms that are displayed for the purpose of collecting individual data by the Lycos Network and/or its advertisers and sponsors. 
  * If you enter a sweepstakes or a contest on the Lycos Network, we will use the information you provided to contact you in the event you win.
  * Lycos may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide information on individual users to the appropriate governmental authorities. In matters involving a danger to personal or public safety, Lycos may voluntarily provide information to appropriate governmental authorities.

**5\. With whom does the Lycos Network share the information that is collected?**   
In order to provide you with content and services that match your interests, the Lycos Network has relationships with many of the best services and content companies. Many of these services also require registration to make them function properly. You can recognize most of these sites by the joint branding of Lycos and such companies. For example, if you see a logo in the upper-right corner of the page that says 'Powered by ______', you are on a co-branded site. Other third-party relationships are "private label" relationships where a Product or Service partner provides Lycos with technology, services and/or content under Lycos Network branding. Whenever you provide registration information on co-branded or private label sites, that data may be shared with the partners. You should make every effort to read the individual privacy policies of the partners, and make an informed decision on your own whether or not to continue based upon these sites' privacy practices and your own discretion. You may opt-out of sharing your information with such partners by choosing not to use that service or content. 

The following is a list of third-party companies with whom Lycos has contracted to provide you Products and Services. This list may expand or change from time to time.

_Lycos Free Internet Access._  
Lycos contracts with 1stUp, Inc. to be the technology provider for Lycos Free Internet Access Service. For more information about 1stUp’s privacy policy, click [here](http://www.1stup.com/subscriber.html). 

_Reminder Services_.  
Lycos contracts with LifeMinders.com ("LifeMinders") to provide a free service that e-mails you weekly reminders and timely tips that you personalize. For more information about LifeMinders' privacy policy, click [here](http://www.lifeminders.com/privacy/index.asp).

_Online Calendar Services_.  
Lycos contracts with AnyDay.com, Inc. to provide its users with online calendar services. For more information about the AnyDay privacy policy, click [here](http://www.anyday.com/privacy_policy.html). 

_Lycos Instant Messaging_.  
Lycos contracts with America Online ("AOL") to provide the Lycos Network with instant messaging services (AIM). For more information on AOL’s privacy policy, click [here](http://www.aol.com/info/privacy.html). 

_Lycos Unified Messaging_.  
Lycos contracts with ThinkLink, Inc.("ThinkLink") to provide Lycos users with Internet Integrated Messaging -- combined voicemail, email, fax, and paging service accessible over the phone and on the Internet. For more information about ThinkLink’s privacy policy, click [here](http://www.thinklink.com/misc/privacy.htm). 

_Lycos Auctions and Classifieds_.  
Lycos contracts with FairMarket, Inc. ("FairMarket"), to provide auction and classified services for the Lycos Network. For more information about FairMarket’s privacy policy click [here](http://www.fairmarket.com/company/legal.htm#privacy). 

_Lycos Rewards_.  
Lycos contracts with NetCentives, Inc. ("NetCentives"), the leading developer of online rewards and loyalty programs, to provide the Lycos Rewards program for Lycos Network users. For more information about NetCentives Privacy Policy, click [here](http://www.netcentives.com/).

_Club Lycos Credit Card_  
Lycos Fleet Credit Card Services ("Fleet"), a subsidiary of FleetBoston Financial, contracted to bring Lycos users co-branded credit card services. For more information about Fleet’s privacy policy, click [here](http://www.fleet.com/afpp.html).

_Lycos Affiliate Services_.   
Lycos contracts with Be Free, Inc. to provide Traffic Affiliate Program services for the Lycos Network. For more information about Be Free's privacy policy, click [here](http://www.befree.com/docs/includes/privacy.htm). 

_Lycos Shop_.   
Please note that, when you purchase goods or services through Lycos Shop, your credit card and identifying information will be provided to third parties in order to verify the credit card data. Furthermore, the data you submit in connection with your use of the Lycos Shop will be provided to individual merchants from whom you order goods or services. Please review carefully the privacy policies of particular merchants that you access through Lycos Shop. Because we take your privacy and security concerns seriously, Lycos Shop took action to ensure that, when you use the Lycos Shop Shopping Cart, the personal data you submit (including your credit card number, billing, and shipping information) is passed through "secure servers." Lycos Shop accomplishes this through technology provided by [Verisign](http://www.verisign.com/). Verisign is a member of the [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.com/) program. For the vast majority of purchases made through the Lycos Shop cart, your credit card is charged electronically and your actual account number is never presented to the merchant from whom you have purchased. 

_Free Online Lottery_.   
Lycos contracts with PlasmaNet, Inc. ("FreeLotto") to provide its users with free online lottery games. When Lycos Gamesville members enter the FreeLotto site through Lycos Gamesville and register to play FreeLotto games, Lycos Gamesville shares registration data with FreeLotto. FreeLotto will use that registration data in accordance with its privacy policy. For more information about the FreeLotto privacy policy, click [here](http://www.freelotto.com/PrivacyPolicy.asp). 

In addition to finding co-branded sites, you will find direct links on our site to sites offered by third parties. Some of these sites are authorized to use the Lycos Network brands and/or logos. No third-party sites are covered by this Privacy Policy. If you feel that a site using a Lycos Network brand and/or logo does not follow an acceptable privacy policy, please contact the Lycos Privacy Site Coordinator by email at [privacy@lycos.com](mailto:privacy@lycos.com). 

**6\. How can you access, edit or delete your information?**   
The Lycos Network provides its registered users the ability to access and edit the personal information in their user profiles. Currently, to access and edit your personal information, you have to go to the specific Lycos Network site where you registered. For locations where you can access and edit your personal information, click on one or more of the following:

  1. [http://my.lycos.com](http://my.lycos.com/). Click on the "My Info" link at the top of the page. You will need to use your Lycos Network user ID and password. 
  2. [http://www.gamesville.com/html_gv/gv_change_registration.htm](http://www2.gamesville.com/html_gv/gv_change_registration.htm). You will need your Lycos Gamesville username and password.
  3. [http://comm.lycos.com/](http://comm.lycos.com/). Click "Options" then "Account Info" on left. You will need to use your Lycos Network user ID and password. 
  4. [http://tripod.lycos.com](http://tripod.lycos.com/). Click "My Account" then "change your password." You will need to use your Lycos Network user ID and password. 
  5. [http://auctions.lycos.com](http://auctions.lycos.com/). Login. Click on "Check My Account" then "update your user profile." You will need to use your Lycos Network user ID, password and email address. 
  6. [http://shop.lycos.com](http://shop.lycos.com/). Login. Click on "Update My Info." You will need to use your Lycos Network user ID, password and email address. 
  7. [http://rewards.lycos.com](http://rewards.lycos.com/). Click on "My Rewards Account" on the left. You will need to use your Lycos Network user ID and password. 
  8. [http://mambo.lycos.com](http://mambo.lycos.com/). Click on members login. Then click on "My Info." You will need to use your Lycos Network user ID and password.

**7\. What is the opt-out policy for the Lycos Network?**  
The Lycos Network offers you the ability to opt-out of receiving information on Lycos Network updates and new services, as well as direct mail offers from selected Lycos Network partners and sponsors. This is done at the point of initial collection of information and during the editing or updating process. The instructions to opt out of most Lycos Network email newsletters and direct mail communications are the same as the instructions listed above for editing user information profiles. In addition, all Lycos Network newsletters and direct email communications have easy-to-follow unsubscribe instructions at the bottom. 

You can go directly to the following unsubscribe sites for selected Wired newsletters and Lycos Gamesville newsletters or follow the unsubscribe instructions found at the bottom of each email communication. 

  1. HotFlash: [http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/hotflash.html](http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/hotflash.html)
  2. Webmonkey/Elbow Grease (ASCII/text-only version): [http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/webmonkey.html](http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/webmonkey.html)
  3. Webmonkey Frontdoor: [http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/webmonkey-frontdoor.html](http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/webmonkey-frontdoor.html)
  4. Wired News Daily (ASCII/text-only version): [http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/wn_ascii/](http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/wn_ascii.html)
  5. Cocktail: [http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/cocktail.html](http://www.hotwired.com/email/unsub/cocktail.html)
  6. If you would prefer never to receive email announcements or newsletters from Wired Digital again, you may request this at: [http://www.hotwired.com/email/never_email.html](http://www.hotwired.com/email/never_email.html)
  7. Gamesville Times and Deal-a-Rama: [http://www.gamesville.com/cgi-bin/editMyGamesville](http://www2.gamesville.com/cgi-bin/editMyGamesville)?

**8\. What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?**   
The Lycos Network has security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. Only authorized employees have access to the information you provide us and strict rules on Lycos Network employees who have access either to the databases that store user information or to the servers that host our services. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we make every effort to prevent such unfortunate occurrences. Any other particularly sensitive information, such as your credit card number collected for a commerce transaction at Lycos Shop or to purchase premium services from Lycos Quote, is encrypted prior to transmission. 

You are ultimately responsible for the security of your Lycos Network ID and password. Please take care when using and storing them. Lycos recommends that you do not divulge your password to anyone. You should log out of your browser at the end of each computer session to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence, especially if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

**9\. The Lycos Network notice regarding the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)?**   
The Lycos Network, in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) of 1998, provides notice to parents of children under 13 that: 

  * The Lycos Network may collect personal information from children under 13 years of age in order to provide them with access to services and content on the Lycos Network;
  * The Lycos Network needs the consent of parents or guardians to collect, use and disclose personally identifiable information about children under 13; 
  * The Lycos Network has created a mechanism by which parents and guardians can provide consent;
  * The Lycos Network may not require children under 13 to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of participation;
  * The Lycos Network has created a mechanism by which parents or guardians can, upon verification, review their children’s personal information, ask to have that information deleted, and refuse to allow any further collection or use of their children’s personal information.

In order to provide consent for your child, please click on the link below, and sign up for a Lycos Family Membership.

With a Lycos Family Membership, both you and your child will have access to the best the Web has to offer. In signing up for a Lycos Family Membership, you will need to provide a major credit card to verify that you are older than 18 and the child's parent or guardian. This is for verification only; your card will not be charged.

If you have any questions about this Notice, about the Lycos Family Membership, or about the collection or maintenance of your child’s personal information anywhere on the Lycos Network, please contact: 

Child Privacy Site Coordinator   
Lycos, Inc.   
400-2 Totten Pond Road   
Waltham, MA 02154   
1-877-Lycos-08 (1-877-592-6708)

This Notice also includes the following information concerning data collection practices on the Lycos Network with regards to children under 13 years of age:

  1. What types of personal information the Lycos Network collects from children and how it is collected;
  2. What operators are collecting or maintaining the information on the Lycos Network;
  3. How do the operators use the information; and
  4. How parents can register, review, edit and delete their child’s personal information;

The Lycos Network encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered on the sites that they visit. No information should be submitted to or posted at the Lycos Network by visitors and registered users under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian.

  1. **What types of personal information does the Lycos Network collect from children and how is it collected?**

The Lycos Network is proud to provide children with access to the best educational and entertainment content and services available online. In order to provide high quality services, and in order for certain of these services to function properly, the Lycos Network collects information from users who are under the age of 13. 

The Lycos Network collects three types of information from children: anonymous information, information that can be tied to particular user’s computer or to the systems used by users to gain Internet access, and personally identifiable information that is specific to a person’s identity. Each time a visitor comes to a Lycos Network site, the Lycos collects some information to improve the overall quality of the online experience. Lycos collects the visitor's IP address (e.g., whether the user is logged on from ibm.com or Lycos Free Internet Access), referral data (e.g., the address of the last URL a user visited prior to clicking through to a Lycos Network site), and browser and platform type (e.g., Internet Explorer and MacIntosh platform). The Lycos Network also collects and maintains in an aggregated anonymous form, search terms from its HotBot and Lycos Search services across the Network for internal reporting and targeted advertising. Lycos collects this user information for purposes of product monitoring, product improvement, and targeted advertising. 

In addition to anonymous data and information that can be tied to a particular user’s computer or to systems used for Internet access, the Lycos Network may also collect personally identifiable information that is specific to a person’s identity. By personally identifiable information, Lycos means information that tells us specifically who you and your child are, such as your names and email address. 

Lycos collects such personally identifiable information about children in two ways:

  1. Most of the personally identifiable information is gathered when you register for a Lycos Family Membership. If you choose to register your child--and Lycos hopes you do-- you may provide Lycos with your child’s name, email address, birth date, gender and zip code. Once you sign up for a Lycos Family Membership your child is given a Lycos Network ID and is able to take full advantage of the many offerings around the Lycos Network that are available to children under 13. Certain offerings such as Chat, Message Boards, Clubs, and purchases through Lycos Shop, Lycos Auctions and Lycos Classified are not available to children. In addition, some areas of the Lycos Network do not require registration. For instance, Lycos does not register users for Lycos Zone (although some activities that are accessible through Lycos Zone are operated by third party service providers who do register users and post their own privacy policies regarding how they collect, maintain, and use that information). 
  2. If your child contacts the Lycos Network, Lycos may keep a record of that correspondence. Lycos only uses the information provided to respond to the e-mail.

In addition to the personally identifiable information that is specific to a person’s identity, which the Lycos Network collects during registration, Lycos also collects other information "passively" using "cookies." A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is stored on the hard drive of your child’s computer. This unique number identifies your child’s browser -- but not your child -- whenever he or she visits one of the sites in the Lycos Network. A cookie will not let a web site know any personally identifiable information about your child that is specific to your child’s identity, such as his/her real name, physical address, or email address. It is merely a way of keeping track of preferences set by a user and activity engaged in by that user without tying that data to personally identifiable information that is specific to the user’s identity, such as the user’s name, physical address, or email address. Because cookies are only text files, they cannot run on your child’s computer, be used to search the computer for other information or transmit any information to anyone.

To help serve you and your child better Lycos uses cookies to:

  * Keep track of the activities of particular users in order to offer and provide customizable and personalized services. For example, cookies allow Lycos to save preferences for you and your children so that you won't have to re-enter them each next time you visit. 
  * Measure traffic patterns. Without cookies, it could be difficult for Lycos to know which services are more popular than others. This helps us improve existing services and introduce new ones. 
  * Estimate audience size. Cookies help us know whether or not users have seen particular displays, including advertising, so Lycos does not bore you with the same material over and over again.

The use of cookies is now an industry standard, and you'll find them used on most major web sites. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser either to notify you when you've received a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies. Certain sites will not function properly if you set your browser to not accept cookies. 

**_Lycos’ relationship with DoubleClick_**  
Lycos has contracted with DoubleClick, Inc. ("DoubleClick") to use its DART ad serving service to manage ad serving and reporting functions. When DoubleClick is serving ads to you and your child, it does not collect any personally identifiable information about you, such as your name or email address. Lycos does not share any personally identifiable information from any registered users with DoubleClick. That means Lycos does not share with DoubleClick personally identifiable information from our users under the age of 13. However, to enable DoubleClick to compile meaningful reports and to better serve advertising to you and your child, DoubleClick collects the following types of non-personally-identifiable information about users who are served ads via DoubleClick technology:

  * IP address from which DoubleClick may infer a user’s geographic location, company, and type and size of organization. 
  * Domain type (i.e., .com, .net, or .edu.). 
  * Standard information included with every communication sent on the Internet. Information which DoubleClick can infer from this standard information includes your browser version and type (i.e., Netscape or Internet Explorer), operating system (i.e., windows or DOS), browser language (i.e., Java or Unix), service provider (i.e., MindSpring or AOL), and your local time. 
  * How you utilize the pages you visit within a DoubleClick client's site (e.g. which pages you view). 
  * Keyword search terms (e.g. if you do a search on "homes," you may be shown advertisements for mortgage companies).

DoubleClick uses cookies to better understand your web surfing behavior and enhance your web viewing experience. The cookies do not damage your system or files in any way. It works like this: When you are first served an ad by DoubleClick, DoubleClick assigns you a unique number and records that number in the cookie file of your computer. Then, when you and your child visit a web site on which DoubleClick serves ads, DoubleClick reads this number to help serve ads to you. The cookie can help ensure that you and your child do not see the same ad over and over again. Cookies can also help advertisers measure how you and your child utilize a Lycos site. This information helps our advertisers cater their ads to your needs.

Although Lycos users cannot opt-out of the advertising process, DoubleClick offers you the ability to control the data collection and targeting process by using a "blank" or "opt-out cookie" to prevent any data from being associated with your browser or you individually. By denying DoubleClick’s cookies, ads delivered to you by Doubleclick can only be targeted based on the non-personally identifiable information that is available from the Internet environment, such as browser type and Internet service provider. Your opt-out will be effective for the entire life of your browser or until you delete the cookie file on your hard drive. To learn more about how to opt-out, please [click here](http://www.doubleclick.net/company_info/about_doubleclick/privacy/privacy2.htm).

**
  2. What operators are collecting or maintaining the information on the Lycos Network
**

The Lycos Network does not knowingly permit children under the age of 13 to register without the verifiable consent of their parents or guardians. The best way for parents to give verifiable consent to Lycos is by signing up for a Lycos Family Membership. When you provide information about yourself and your child during registration for a Lycos Family Membership, that information is collected and maintained by the Lycos Network and, if the functionality of the service so requires, by the providers of those specific services and content. The Lycos Family Membership allows access for children under 13 to the following registration-based Services operated by the Lycos Network:

  * My Lycos, for personalized start pages and other content;
  * Tripod and Angelfire for personal web page building and hosting services;
  * Lycos Communications for web-based email services;

As of April 21, 2000, children under the age of 13 will not be able to register for Chat, Message Boards and Clubs on the Lycos Network. Use of Lycos Shop, Lycos Auctions and Lycos Classifieds are restricted to individuals who are 18 years of age or older.

In addition to the information collected by the Lycos Network, certain non-Lycos-affiliated companies collect information through the Lycos Network. By registering for a Lycos Family Membership, you are also agreeing to have your child’s information shared with the following operators: 

  * DoubleClick, Inc.: ad serving, as described above;
  * FairMarket, Inc.: auction and classified ads services;
  * Mambo, Inc.: online invitation services;
  * Anyday, Inc.: online calendar services;
  * NetCentives, Inc.: online rewards programs;
  * 1stUp, Inc.: free Internet access;
  * Alfy, Inc.: interactive games and activities for children;
  * Bonus.com, Inc. : interactive games for children; and 
  * Cybersurfari, Inc.: interactive games for children

****
  3. **How do the operators use the information?**

As described above, DoubleClick collects information passively. The other operators collect registration information and also collect information passively. These other operators run individual services within the Lycos Network and need access to user information in order for those services to function properly. Lycos and the other operators listed in this Notice are the only entities that knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. Should other operators collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 through the Lycos Network in the future, Lycos will update this Notice. Neither Lycos nor the other operators listed will use your child’s personally identifiable information for external marketing purposes without your permission. Neither Lycos nor the other operators will share rent or sell your child’s personally identifiable information with any third party without your permission. Questions regarding the collection, maintenance, and use of information by these other operators should be directed to [Lycos’ Child Privacy Site Coordinator](mailto:privacy@lycos.com) at [privacy@lycos.com](mailto:privacy@lycos.com).

Be aware that certain links from Lycos Network sponsors and advertisers take you to other sites that may collect personally identifiable information about you and your children. The Lycos Network hopes that all third parties involved adhere to legal policies regarding the privacy of our users. However, this Notice does not cover third party data collection practices, and the Lycos Network does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties. 

**
  4. How can parents register, review, edit and delete their child’s personal information?
**
 ****

A parent must register for a Lycos Network Family Membership in order for a child to register for Lycos Network services. After signing up for a Lycos Family Membership, a parent can add one or more children to the membership, thus giving consent for the child to sign up for their own Membership to Lycos Network services. 

With a Lycos Family Membership a parent is able to: 

  * Add one or multiple children to a Lycos Family Membership
  * Register a child for a new Lycos Network Member Name
  * Add a child's existing Lycos Member Name (you’ll need their member name and password).
  * View and Edit a child’s membership information
  * Modify a child's password 
  * Delete a child’s account

During the process of registering for a Lycos Family Membership, the parent needs to supply a valid credit card number. This is because Lycos is required by COPPA to verify a parent or guardian’s identity, and to ensure the parent or guardian is over 18 years of age. Currently, Lycos has determined a credit card authorization to be the most efficient and effective way for us to verify you are an adult and are giving accurate information. The credit card will not be charged, and only the last 4 digits and a transaction number will be stored as proof of transaction. Lycos accepts Visa and MasterCard for account verification. In the future, Lycos may use different mechanisms for verifying age.

_

How to add a child to the Lycos Family Membership:

_

After you have signed up for a Lycos Family Membership, go to the Family Membership Home Page and click on "Add Child." You'll then be able to add a child by either:

  * Registering your child for a new Lycos Network Member Name 
  * Adding an existing Lycos Network Member Name to your Family Membership. You'll need your child's Lycos Network Member Name and Password. 

When you add a child to the Lycos Family, your child's membership is listed as part of your family membership. This means that your child is now able to use all of the Lycos Network services.

Note: It is the policy of the Lycos Network to permit parent and guardians to add only children under the age of 18 to a Lycos Family Membership.

_

How to return to the Lycos Family Membership page:

_

When you sign-up for a Lycos Family Membership, it is best to add this page to your list of "Favorites," or to bookmark it in your browser. When you return to this page, you will be asked to supply your Family Membership Name and Password to see the Family Membership page.

Additionally, you can get to this page by signing in to other Lycos Network services (My Lycos, Lycos Communications , Tripod, Angelfire, Lycos Shop, Rewards, Auctions) and going to the User Info Update page. There will be a link to Lycos Family Membership on this page.

_

How to view/edit a child's member information:

_

To edit a child's membership information, go to the Lycos Family Membership page **** and click the "View/Edit" link next to the child's Lycos Member Name. You will need to have your Lycos Family Membership ID and password in order to access your Lycos Family Membership profile. You'll be taken to the child’s account update page where you can edit their Membership information. 

Much of this information is required for your child to be able to use Lycos Network service. However, you’ll be able to supervise what information your child gives, and ensure that the information is accurate. 

You can also pick a new password for your child, retype it to confirm, then click submit. The child will need to use this new password the next time they sign in to any Lycos Network service. 

Please note: Once your child signs in, they can change their password again. Using this feature does not prevent them from getting a new password. However, you will always be able to change it back.

_

How to delete a child’s membership:

_

Return to the Lycos Family Membership page, and click on "delete" next to a specific child. You will be prompted to enter your password again for security purposes, and then the child’s Membership will be changed so that the child can no longer log in to any Lycos Network service.

**10\. What additional measures does Lycos take to protect children online?**   
The Lycos Network believes that it is particularly important to protect the privacy of children -- online, offline, anywhere and everywhere. Lycos recommends that parents and kids try LycosZone, a web guide designed especially for Internet users between the ages of 7 and 12. LycosZone is proud to work with some of the top providers of children entertainment and homework resources on the Web. 

LycosZone does not collect any personally identifiable information from children - protection that goes beyond the requirements of the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). The Lycos Network, however, is a general audience network of web sites that has content and services of interest to individuals of all ages. When children under age 13 attempt to register with Lycos, we ask them to have a parent or guardian establish a Lycos Family Membership. The Family Membership feature allows the Lycos Network to obtain verifiable consent from a parent or guardian before we collect any registration information from a child we know to be under 13 years of age. In addition, Family Membership allows parents to access their child's Lycos account, edit account information and better control their child's personal information. To learn more about Lycos Network Family Membership, please see our [Family Membership](http://www.lycosnetwork.com/family_request) page.

Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to anyone online. Lycos does not knowingly share personal information about users under the age of 13 with third parties and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of age, without their permission. In addition, Lycos will not send any direct email offers to users who indicate they are under the age of 13. Lycos strongly suggests that parents read the [online bulletin](http://www.lycos.com/lycosinc/safetyterms.html) published by, and reprinted with the permission of, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children and that they make use of the [Parental Controls](http://searchguard.lycos.com/) available on the Lycos Network.

**11\. What you can do to better protect yourself on the Internet**   

****
  1. **Know the risks.**   
When you communicate with others online, you should be aware that, when disclosing personal information such as one's actual name, member name, e-mail address, etc., on a web page, in a newsgroup, chat room or forum, that information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties, outside the Lycos Network. Some of the e-mail you receive may be useful to you, but some may not. In an effort to curtail unsolicited e-mail, Lycos blocks certain e-mail addresses and domains from sending e-mail to e-mail addresses at our domains. 
****
  2. **Educate yourself.**   
Search the Web for as much information as you can about how to protect your privacy. Look for a privacy statement in the sites you visit. A good place to start is [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/) \-- an independent, non-profit privacy initiative dedicated to building users' trust and confidence in the Internet. Please visit the Federal Trade Commission’s web site and read information on being a [Savvy Internet Traveler](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html) and other [privacy initiatives](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html). Additional privacy resources can be found at by clicking on any of the following links: 

**Department of Education: Parents Guide to the Internet**  
<http://www.ed.gov/pubs/parents/internet/>

**Better Business Bureau (BBB)**  

**The Privacy Rights Clearinghouse**  
<http://www.privacyrights.org/>

**Center for Democracy and Technology**  
<http://www.cdt.org/privacy/> \- Data Privacy  
<http://www.cdt.org/privacy/guide/> \- Guide to Online Privacy 

**Direct Marketing Association (DMA)**  
<http://www.the-dma.org/>

**Electronic Frontier Foundation** \- non-profit dedicated to protecting public interest in online privacy. [http://www.eff.org](http://www.eff.org/)

**EPIC.org** (Electronic Privacy Information Center)   

**Georgetown Internet Privacy Study**  

**NetCoalition.com**  

**Network Advertising Initiative**  

**Online Privacy Alliance**  

  3. **Tell your children: "Never talk to strangers!"**   
While the Lycos Network works hard to protect children on its sites, Lycos cannot protect their privacy once they leave. Please teach children to not give out their names or other personal information to anyone on the Internet. They should also be instructed not to fill out any forms or register at any website without your knowledge and consent. Take advantage of the online resources for parents available on the Lycos Network, such as [SearchGuard](http://searchguard.lycos.com/) and [GetNetWise](http://www.lycos.com/parentalcontrol/getnetwise.html).
  4. **Use PGP (Pretty Good Privacy)**[http://www.pgp.com](http://www.pgp.com/) or another encryption program.  

Last updated April 13, 2000.
